SAMUEL OLANIYAN

Calgary, AB | 403-888-1568 | olaniyansamuel2015@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/samuel-olaniyan/

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A Passionate and highly motivated full-stack software developer with over two years of experience collaborating with web designers and using a variety of programming languages and tools to develop efficient, reliable, and accessible products. An exceptional problem-solver with four years of finance experience, allowing him to bring a unique blend of software engineering and financial knowledge to build scalable products on time and within budget.

Skills & Expertise

Programming languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, C#.

Front-end development: HTML, CSS, React.

Back-end development: Django, NodeJS, Flask, .Net.Database management: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.

• Cloud frameworks: AWS, Azure.

• UX design: Figma.

Enterprise Architecture: Microsoft Visio, PowerBI and Power Platform.

• Other tools: Git, GitHub, Docker

• Interpersonal Skills: Communication, Time management, and Problem-solving.

Relevant Work Experience

Enterprise Architect

Scottish Water, Aberdeen, United Kingdom

2022

- Developed a vendor-applications lifecycle gap management framework, which helped prevent disruptions to business, ensured software assets are regularly updated and saved costs.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and develop scalable and flexible systems that meet the needs of the business.
- Conducted business requirements research and evaluated the impact of solutions on the overall system to achieve a better synergy between IT and the business.

Back-End Developer

TYCOM Limited, Aberdeen, United Kingdom

2022

- Utilized C# and .NET to develop custom APIs and integrations with third-party systems that helped improve efficiency and streamlined processes for the company.
- Collaborated with front-end developers to design, optimize, and implement MVC-based web process automation that reduced overall processing time by 30%.
- Contributed to the development of internal documentation and guidelines which have played a significant role in improving efficiency and ensuring consistent quality across all projects.

Front-End Developer 2020 - 2022

MerchBro Enterprises, Lagos, Nigeria

- Developed responsive and intuitive user interfaces for internal applications using ReactJS and other plugins which led to an increase in productivity and a high-quality user experience.
- Created reusable components and implemented efficient data management strategies to improve the performance and scalability of the applications.

- Assessed the technical feasibility of UI designs and ensured the final output is aligned with the organization's branding to ensure consistent product quality across all applications.
- Trained new team members and participated in code reviews to ensure high-quality code.

Senior Treasury Analyst

2017 - 2021

Access Bank PLC, Lagos, Nigeria

- Monitored and analyzed the company's cash flow, identifying opportunities for improvement and implementing solutions to optimize cash management.
- Developed and maintained strong relationships with banks and financial institutions, negotiating favourable terms for loans and other financial instruments.
- Conducted detailed financial analysis to support decision-making and strategic planning.
- Led a team of five that contributed more than 20% to the organization's revenue in 2021 (the highest single contribution by any team).

Education

MSc. Information Technology

University of Aberdeen, United Kingdom

2022-2023

 Coursework included enterprise & advanced software development, software project management, web development, information security, human-computer interaction database management and big data.

BSc. Chemical Engineering

University of Ilorin, Nigeria

2010-2015

Projects

- Custom Console application for tracking deleted jobs (TYCOM Limited, Aberdeen)
 - Developed a real-time console application using C# and .Net that generates a report of all deleted jobs scheduled to be moved to immutable storage.
- E-Ledger Accounting software (MerchBro Enterprises, Lagos, Nigeria)
 - Worked on the design and development of the user interface of simple accounting software that provides an up-to-date overview of the financial position as well as a cash flow projection.

Certifications

Microsoft Power Platform Fundamentals (PL-900)	2022
Professional Scrum Master (PSM1), Scrum.Org	2022
Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner, IBM	2020